
[Subtitles]

CIN_Intro_01="Excitement continues to build as city centers across the globe prepare for the 20th anniversary of Unification Day."
CIN_Intro_02="Thousands line up at the site of the Great Accord, celebrating the formation of the ADVENT Coalition."
CIN_Intro_03="In keeping with their promise to humanity, 12 new gene therapy clinics will be opening in select cities by the end of the new year."
CIN_Intro_04="Despite the attack by fringe elements, operations at the new facility in Paris thankfully remain unaffected."
CIN_Intro_05="In response to the unprovoked intrusion on the eve of our most beloved celebration, the Speaker reaches out to us..."
CIN_Intro_06="A small number of dissidents again repeat the mistakes of the old world. Striking as we celebrate a benevolent savior who time and again offers only friendship and compassion. Yet these trivial actions could never break the bond between humanity and the Elders..."
CIN_Intro_07="Peacekeeping forces have already made several preemptive arrests of known collaborators."
CIN_Intro_08="ADVENT again assures all citizens that today's celebrations will continue as planned."
CIN_Intro_09="Perfect."
CIN_Intro_10="The ADVENT Administration reminds you to report all suspicious activity to your nearest peace keeper. Remember, only together can we build a better tomorrow."
CIN_Intro_11="Approaching position."
CIN_Intro_12="You were right, they've definitely got their hands full today."
CIN_Intro_12a="Stay focused..."
CIN_Intro_13="Prep Gatecrasher, 60 seconds."
CIN_Intro_15="Mor Balaten."
CIN_Intro_16="Mor Balaten!"
CIN_Intro_17="Now."
CIN_Intro_18="Signal received. Loud and clear."
CIN_Intro_19="OK, Gatecrasher, your turn."

CIN_TP_PostIntro_01=" Advent forces are swarming to the blast point, we need to move on the package before they figure out what we're up to."

CIN_SP_02_FacilityReveal_01="They're holding position. We're gonna have to go through them. Stay out of sight until we're ready to strike."
CIN_SP_02_FacilityReveal_02="Copy that."

CIN_SP_03_AdventResponse_01="Remind me to thank the old man."
CIN_SP_03_AdventResponse_02="You and me both."

CIN_SP_04_CentralCurbStomp_01="Morta... Beltor..."
CIN_SP_04_CentralCurbStomp_02="She's calling reinforcements!  Stop that-"
CIN_SP_04_CentralCurbStomp_03="...transmission."
CIN_SP_04_CentralCurbStomp_04="Central, reporting in."
CIN_SP_04_CentralCurbStomp_05="You're late. What have you been doing down there?"
CIN_SP_04_CentralCurbStomp_06="Taking in the sights."
CIN_SP_04_CentralCurbStomp_07="What the hell are these things?!"
CIN_SP_04_CentralCurbStomp_08="They're us. Least they used to be. Human hybrid soldiers. ADVENT's reward for obedience and service."
CIN_SP_04_CentralCurbStomp_09="We've all heard rumors. I just never believed it was true."
CIN_SP_04_CentralCurbStomp_10="No one wanted to. But we find what we're looking for today, I promise you that's gonna change."
CIN_SP_04_CentralCurbStomp_11="Let's move."

CIN_SP_06_RescueCommander_01="Moving to secure the package."
CIN_SP_06_RescueCommander_02="Let's hope our intel was good."
CIN_SP_06_RescueCommander_03="This is the place."
CIN_SP_06_RescueCommander_04="Are you sure?"
CIN_SP_06_RescueCommander_04a="Yes."
CIN_SP_06_RescueCommander_05="Looks like there's an access panel attached. If you get me a better look I might be able to-"
CIN_SP_06_RescueCommander_06="Next time..."
CIN_SP_06_RescueCommander_07="Let's get out of here."

CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_01="Carefully! There's potentially decades of atrophy to contend with!"
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_02="Wish we had more time..."
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_03="I don't disagree. But as it stands now we risk losing the patient if we don't begin the removal procedure immediately."
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_04="We're ready."
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_05="Good. Then let's get on with it."
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_06="Remarkable!"
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_07="Just like 20 years ago..."
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_08="...we were still calling it a war back then."
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_09="We had no idea what was coming."
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_10="...response from the cerebral cortex. Good. Prepping for cranial intrusion."
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_11="...I've managed to identify the connection. Preparing to make final incision."
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_12="These readings are getting really erratic..."
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_13="Of course they are. These implants were never designed to be removed. We are risking severe-"
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_14="No Plan B here people. Do it!"
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_15="Doctor!"
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_16="No signal..."
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_17="...pupillary response normal. Vitals stabilizing. Procedure complete."
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_18="Told 'em it would take more than that to keep you down."
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_19="Welcome back...Commander."
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_20="Glad to see you're finally coming out it. Don't envy the headache you must have though..."
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_21="Still, can't fault Dr. Tygan. Especially as no one's even attempted something like this before."
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_22="Easy - we're still not entirely sure what they did to you...that chip was buried halfway into your skull."
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_23="Lost a lot of good soldiers looking for you over the years. Almost gave up hope you were still out there. Acted on the intel as soon as I got word."
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_24="Not sure what you remember but a lot's changed. Did the best I could but the last 20 years have been tough without you."
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_25="You feel like catching up, Shen has the archive up and running on your terminal."
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_26="Otherwise, I'd go see Dr. Tygan when you're ready. There's some things you should know. He'll be better at explaining them than me."
CIN_TP_CommanderAwakens_27="It's damn good to have you back, Commander."

CIN_Welcome_Labs_Part1_01="Impressive isn't it. Capable of generating immense power, yet completely harmless to human life. If only the same could be said for the rest of the aliens' technology, Commander."
CIN_Welcome_Labs_Part1_02="Dr. Richard Tygan, Chief Science Officer. I am responsible for the entirety of our research here, as well as the procedure you so recently underwent. Welcome to my lab, such as it is."
CIN_Welcome_Labs_Part1_03="I'm not sure what Central may have told you, but we found something while removing you from the alien stasis suit."
CIN_Welcome_Labs_Part1_04="A device implanted directly in your occipital lobe. Had I access to the equipment available to me during my tenure at ADVENT I would already know the precise nature of its function. However, given time, and your approval of course Commander, I assure you I will find out."
CIN_Welcome_Labs_Part1_05="Which brings to light an additional point. Though aspects of this facility are indeed impressive, I am but one man. Were you to direct additional support personnel and resources to me, I could substantially improve the speed of all our research. Farewell, Commander."

CIN_Welcome_Labs_Part2_01="So much of my own research based upon this simple design. If only I had known."
CIN_Welcome_Labs_Part2_02="Ah, Commander. Excellent timing. There's been some, progress."
CIN_Welcome_Labs_Part2_03="I've managed to break down several key components of the "chip" implanted into your skull. My analysis reveals that its primary function was that of a conduit, passing a vast amount of data directly to your cerebral cortex."
CIN_Welcome_Labs_Part2_04="With the primary connection severed, much of that data is lost. Several fragments do remain, however."Ghosts" if you will. Observe."
CIN_Welcome_Labs_Part2_05="Tactical combat simulations. Wargames. The sheer volume of encounters you were processing was astounding. It... it is truly remarkable that you survived as long as you did."
CIN_Welcome_Labs_Part2_06="Though this may seem disconcerting, there is still some "good news". This "chip" bears a striking resemblance to a medical implant I briefly assisted in developing at the Gene Therapy Clinic in New Providence."
CIN_Welcome_Labs_Part2_07="My understanding was that the implants were intended for high-ranking ADVENT officers only, Captains or above. Retrieving a chip from such an officer would be the only way to know for certain. A greater understanding of these implants would undoubtedly benefit us all, Commander."

CIN_TP_WelcomeHQ_01="I heard you Shen. When we get the thing, you'll be the first to know."
CIN_TP_WelcomeHQ_02="ATTENTION: UNAUTHORIZED PRESENCE DETECTED."
CIN_TP_WelcomeHQ_03="Commander. Give me a second."
CIN_TP_WelcomeHQ_04="Execute Echelon Protocol."
CIN_TP_WelcomeHQ_05="ATTENTION: SENIOR COMMAND EXCHANGE CONFIRMED."
CIN_TP_WelcomeHQ_06="I had wanted that to be a little more ceremonious, but we've got something."
CIN_TP_WelcomeHQ_07="A local resistance cell just located this "hybrid magnetic power converter" that Shen's been pushing us to find."
CIN_TP_WelcomeHQ_08="They tracked the device to a nearby ADVENT convoy and are attempting to take it down. If we can bring this "converter" back in one piece, we might actually get this place up and running. And give the aliens a real war for a change."
CIN_TP_WelcomeHQ_09="A squad is prepped and ready to launch on your order, Commander. Just give the word."

CIN_WelcomeHQ_NS_01="Commander, good to see you on your feet again. Welcome to the Bridge. The nerve center of our operation."
CIN_WelcomeHQ_NS_02="The aliens have our entire world in their grip. ADVENT controls everything - government, communications, industry, not to mention the military. And it's on us to take it all back."
CIN_WelcomeHQ_NS_03="Resources and time are tight Commander. It will be up to you to decide how to best use both. The ship is yours."

CIN_TP_ShenObtainsFlightDevice_01="Why are you all just standing around?!"
CIN_TP_ShenObtainsFlightDevice_02="It's... perfect! Mmmph. Come on, let's get it inside."

Cin_Welcome_Engineering_01="OK, reworked your repulsors with some of the parts I salvaged from your old engine. Should fix that stabilization problem you had."
Cin_Welcome_Engineering_01a="Come on, Rover, it'll work."
Cin_Welcome_Engineering_02="There."
Cin_Welcome_Engineering_03="Commander! Getting our tech to talk to theirs is harder than you'd think. Lily Shen, Chief Engineer, at your service."
Cin_Welcome_Engineering_04="You were probably expecting to see my father... in all that's happened I'm guessing Central didn't tell you yet. He's... Gone."
Cin_Welcome_Engineering_05="Dad gave everything he had to get us this far. This entire ship is his life's work."
Cin_Welcome_Engineering_05a="I know he would have loved to show you around the place himself."
Cin_Welcome_Engineering_05b="He used to talk about you a lot."
Cin_Welcome_Engineering_06="You can be sure I'm ready to finish what he started. Might not look it, but from here I can fabricate pretty much anything you come up with. And with a little more help... well you'd be amazed with what I can do."
Cin_Welcome_Engineering_07="It was an honor to finally meet you, Commander."

CIN_TP_WelcomeResistance_01="Hello, Commander. The council you once knew is no more. Its membership have all sworn loyalty to the ADVENT Administration."
CIN_TP_WelcomeResistance_02="With one exception. It is good to see you again. In the days since your capture I have done all I can to aid the resistance from the inside. It was these resistance operatives that provided the intel leading to your recent extraction. As of now, resistance forces are currently somewhat... disorganized. If we are to defeat ADVENT and their alien masters, you must change this before it is too late."
CIN_TP_WelcomeResistance_03="What you are seeing are classified reports of missing civilians from across the world. Their numbers are growing. We suspect they have been taken to a nearby ADVENT black site, though its exact location remains unknown."
CIN_TP_WelcomeResistance_04="Time is short, Commander. We need you to take charge of resistance operations throughout the world. Establish contact with the local cells and bring them into the fold. Find this black site and shut it down. Save our world. The clock is ticking. Good luck, Commander."

CIN_TP_AvatarProject_01="Hello, Commander."
CIN_TP_AvatarProject_02="It would seem your recent activities have gotten ADVENT's attention.  Our unwelcome guests are on the move."
CIN_TP_AvatarProject_03="ADVENT has been diverting  considerable resources and personnel to covert facilities across the globe.  The exact details of these operations are highly classified, however they do have one thing in common.  A single word that appears in all their files: Avatar."
CIN_TP_AvatarProject_04="I believe the Blacksite we had previously uncovered to be but a part of this Avatar Project.  Based on what we have uncovered so far its true scope is far greater."
CIN_TP_AvatarProject_05="This Project is being directed from the very top of Advent, from a Source I am still unable to determine.  All attempts to uncover its identity have met with...failure.  It is time to take a more direct approach."
CIN_TP_AvatarProject_06="Though we may not know the exact nature of this Avatar Project we can still disrupt it.  We must root out these hidden facilities with the help of local resistance cells.  Disrupt our enemy's operations and in the process uncover the truth.  Locate the source of this Avatar Project and then destroy it."
CIN_TP_AvatarProject_07="Were the enemy to succeed in their efforts, I am certain it would mean the end for us all. I am confident you will take whatever measures necessary to eliminate this threat, Commander."

CIN_TP_FirstFlight_01="Just stay clear of the perimeter. Understood?"
CIN_TP_FirstFlight_02="Commander, good. I think we've got something here."
CIN_TP_FirstFlight_03="Despite all of ADVENT's efforts, there are still people who refuse to believe their lies."
CIN_TP_FirstFlight_04="And it's time we let them know they're not alone. We've already located a target for our first operation."
CIN_TP_FirstFlight_05="Sir, given our current location there's actually no way the Skyranger could reach that position..."
CIN_TP_FirstFlight_06="Who said anything about the Skyranger."
CIN_TP_FirstFlight_07="Shen - status report, are we ready?"
CIN_TP_FirstFlight_08="Short answer? "Yes". But you might all want to hold onto something."

CIN_TP_BuildOutpost_01="Welcome to the fight."

CIN_TP_PsiNetwork_01="I take it this was... easier than your last procedure Doctor?"
CIN_TP_PsiNetwork_02="Central, Commander. Yes, I find the process to be far less disconcerting when the subject has already expired. The results however... it's best you see for yourself."
CIN_TP_PsiNetwork_03="My autopsy of the ADVENT Captain has confirmed the existence of an implant similar in design to the unit I extracted from the Commander. But there are differences."
CIN_TP_PsiNetwork_04="What kind of differences?"
CIN_TP_PsiNetwork_05="The data you see is being pulled directly from this ADVENT Captain's implant. The sequence here, is essentially you, Commander. Or at least the tactical information they were processing through your mind. As you can see, the data is nearly identical."
CIN_TP_PsiNetwork_06="They were using you against us."
CIN_TP_PsiNetwork_07="Yes. However..."
CIN_TP_PsiNetwork_08="The ADVENT data shows signs of decay. Removing the Commander from their network has likely caused significant damage."
CIN_TP_PsiNetwork_09="Network?"
CIN_TP_PsiNetwork_10="Yes, what we are seeing here is a psionic network. These implants are capable of receiving and transmitting information - a great deal of information, somehow encoded in a stream of psionic energy."
CIN_TP_PsiNetwork_11="My working theory - ADVENT uses this network to augment the tactical readiness of its troops as well as disseminate orders from its Central Command. Observe..."
CIN_TP_PsiNetwork_12="Even in the subject's diminished condition, the implant continues to have an effect. A truly astonishing achievement."
CIN_TP_PsiNetwork_13="Or a weakness..."
CIN_TP_PsiNetwork_14="Potentially - but I'd need direct access to their network to know for sure."
CIN_TP_PsiNetwork_15="I'm guessing that won't be easy."
CIN_TP_PsiNetwork_16="We'd need an active link. And that would mean hacking a live ADVENT Officer."
CIN_TP_PsiNetwork_17="Like I said, not easy."
CIN_TP_PsiNetwork_18="Still, it's the best lead we've got. Your call, Commander."

CIN_TP_ShadowChamberReveal_01="Although I'm impressed with the strides we've made in infiltrating the alien Psionic network, the depths of their technological advancement continue to leave us one step behind."
CIN_TP_ShadowChamberReveal_02="However, with the enhanced decryption capabilities of this chamber, I'm confident we will find a great deal more information than we had previously hoped."

CIN_Retaliation_01="Nothing on the local comms. ADVENT's been quiet lately. I'm guessing we have you to thank for that."
CIN_Retaliation_02="Our pleasure Denmother. Enjoy it while it lasts."
CIN_Retaliation_03="We plan to. Our water purification system..."
CIN_Retaliation_04="Massive signal coming from the ADVENT Network Tower. It's... global. Sir, I think you'll want to see this."
CIN_Retaliation_05="Fellow citizens. For 20 years the ADVENT Coalition has worked tirelessly to repair the ravages and injustices of the old world. Under our stewardship, our cities prosper, our people flourish and our world heals."
CIN_Retaliation_06="And yet, among us, there are still those who would refuse to acknowledge the truth! Who are determined to see all that we have achieved crumble!"
CIN_Retaliation_07="Multiple radar contacts on approach to Haven Alpha-Seven."
CIN_Retaliation_08="That must end. Even as I speak to you today, ADVENT peacekeepers are advancing into the outlying territories...."
CIN_Retaliation_09="You've got incoming on approach!
CIN_Retaliation_10="Your signal's breaking up..."
CIN_Retaliation_11="... to end this scourge once and for all." 
CIN_Retaliation_12="They're right on top of you!"
CIN_Retaliation_13="Losing you Avenger."
CIN_Retaliation_14="Raise them again!"
CIN_Retaliation_15="We will ensure your continued safety and well-being throughout this crisis."
CIN_Retaliation_16="GET YOUR PEOPLE OUT OF THERE!"
CIN_Retaliation_17="With your cooperation we will overcome these radical elements and usher in another 20 years of peace and prosperity."
CIN_Retaliation_18="They don't stand a chance..."
CIN_Retaliation_19="Commander, we should get a squad ready to deploy..."

CIN_TP_AvengerAttacked_01="We've lost power! We're goin' down fast!"
CIN_TP_AvengerAttacked_02="Impossible! There's no damage to the engines! Unless... Must be using an electromagnetic pulse! If I can just bypass all this alien circuitry... hold on!"
CIN_TP_AvengerAttacked_03="Shen."
CIN_TP_AvengerAttacked_04="It's not accepting the transfer! Interface ready... the system is overriding my command!"
CIN_TP_AvengerAttacked_05="SHEN!"
CIN_TP_AvengerAttacked_06="Right."
CIN_TP_AvengerAttacked_07="EMERGENCY POWER ONLINE"
CIN_TP_AvengerAttacked_08="Someone get me a damage report!"
CIN_TP_AvengerAttacked_09="We've got a problem."
CIN_TP_AvengerAttacked_10="Only One?"
CIN_TP_AvengerAttacked_11="They've just dropped some sort of...spike outside. It's generating the same type of pulse that knocked us out of the sky."
CIN_TP_AvengerAttacked_12="They don't want us. They want the ship. Isn't there some way you can override it?"
CIN_TP_AvengerAttacked_13="Not from here."
CIN_TP_AvengerAttacked_14="I can't get our engines online while it's out there!"
CIN_TP_AvengerAttacked_15="Commander, we're gonna have to do this the old fashioned way. Destroying that spike is our only chance at getting outta here. We can't let the aliens take this ship!"

CIN_TP_OldGods_pt1_01="Commander, we're making progress piecing this thing back together... but it hasn't been pretty."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt1_02="Our soldiers completely disabled this unit in the field. What we're hearing is merely a byproduct of electrical impulses - I assure you, it is well past the point of feeling pain."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt1_03="I'll take your word for it, Doctor."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt1_04="I'm sending you a new sequence now."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt1_05="These are coordinates... return coordinates. Think we've got a point of origin! Well... part of one."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt1_06="Something else... something - underneath. One moment."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt1_07="The unit is attempting to block further access."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt1_08="That's not all it's doing! I'm losing the data we've already decrypted."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt1_09="Almost there... just one more adjustment..."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt1_10="Forget the data... it's accessing the Power Core. Overriding my safeties. Increasing power levels to..."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt1_11="Tygan!"
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt1_11a="Sever the connection!"
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt1_12="There."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt1_13="Some sort of fail safe protocol I imagine. The Codex must have intentionally overloaded the interface to prevent any further theft of information."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt1_14="Still, I believe I was one step ahead of it."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt1_15="That's... an enormous amount of data."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt1_16="Yes. And I expect it may take some time to decipher."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt1_17="Better get started."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt1_17a="I don't think we're gonna be able to do that again."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt1_18="I'll proceed with the necessary research and preparation- with your approval of course, Commander. I'd also suggest we look into those coordinates-"
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt1_19="That's IF I can reconstruct the data we lost in the transfer. I just hope it was worth it."

CIN_TP_OldGods_pt2_01="Central, Commander... excellent. My analysis of the fragmented Codex data is almost complete."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt2_02="The information I've uncovered so far outweighs the loss of the shadow chamber, as you'll see..."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt2_03="Is that... an Elder. Haven't seen one in at least a decade."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt2_04="Yes. And I believe I now understand why."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt2_05="The Elders appear to be afflicted with an aggressive form of tissue degeneration. Rapid muscular atrophy to a degree I had not even thought possible."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt2_06="So they're dying. Sounds like our job just got a whole lot easier."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt2_07="As with most things involving this adversary, it's never quite that simple."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt2_08="The Elders have been aggressively searching for a cure to their condition for centuries. Each time they encountered a new species they procured what genetic information and material they required and moved on to the next world. Until now."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt2_09="I believe they found something in us. Something important enough to cause them to take root."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt2_10="A cure?"
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt2_11="Not that I can determine. Several key files were previously deleted as part of something called the Avatar Directive."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt2_12="Avatar. We need those files."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt2_13="Were I to gain access to a fully functioning Codex, I might be able to recover them."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt2_14="Or blow the entire ship to hell this time around."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt2_15="I didn't say I needed the creature here, Bradford. I am confident I could access the unit remotely, provided your soldiers can get close enough to it in the field without destroying it first."
CIN_TP_OldGods_pt2_16="That we can arrange Doctor."

CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_01="...still can't believe it's come to this."
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_02="I truly hope those gruesome images are the worst of what we find today..."
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_03="They're slaughtering us, Doctor. What could be worse?!"
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_04="We're about to find out."
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_04a="I've patched the Shadow Chamber directly into the ship's computer."
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_05="It's been sifting through the material we recovered non-stop since our return. Cataloguing sequences...
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_06="Genetic Sequences. In near infinite combinations. Yet all bearing similar genetic markers. Human markers."
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_07="There must be thousands of them."
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_08="Tens of thousands. And the procedure is still nowhere near complete."
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_09="Which is why we need the ship's computer to find out where they came from."
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_10="By cross referencing them with the data we've managed to hack from the ADVENT network."
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_11="It's...an admission file from one of the Gene Therapy clinics."
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_12="Avatar."
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_13="Just what exactly is in that vial."
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_14="In my worst nightmares, I would never have imagined."
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_15="Doctor."
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_16="I believe we have found the missing civilians."
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_17="That's...that's impossible."
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_18="The gene clinics. Millions of people, just looking for help."
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_19="Medically screened and selected. Suitable candidates taken to that contemptible facility to be processed. Refined into the material we now possess."
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_20="But...why do this?"
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_21="I could not begin to fathom a guess at this point. There exists no research that would ever warrant this..."
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_22="It's genocide, Doctor. And these people are walking right into it!"
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_23="We may not know what they're doing with this stuff, but I think I can find out where it's going."
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_24="Got it. It's a high security production facility - standard defensive complement."
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_25="Then I strongly suggest we pay them a visit, Commander."
CIN_TP_BlacksiteHorror_26="Agreed. The information we gain could prove invaluable towards stopping the aliens' true agenda."

CIN_TP_HumansAreObsolete_01="Just like the one we found the Commander in..."
CIN_TP_HumansAreObsolete_02="On the surface, yes. But in function..."
CIN_TP_HumansAreObsolete_03="Ah, Commander - Excellent. We can begin."
CIN_TP_HumansAreObsolete_04="It is no secret that ADVENT soldiers possess both human and alien genetic characteristics. Preliminary analysis led me to believe that this was the result of direct modifications made to a pre-existing human host. Prisoners, or perhaps even unwitting volunteers."
CIN_TP_HumansAreObsolete_05="See your local Advent recruiter today."
CIN_TP_HumansAreObsolete_06="However, the reality is something else entirely."
CIN_TP_HumansAreObsolete_07="The ADVENT troopers at the facility we discovered, including the specimen before you, were manufactured."
CIN_TP_HumansAreObsolete_08="Each soldier possesses a unique genetic code. Predominately human of course - but with some fragments left open..."
CIN_TP_HumansAreObsolete_09="Left open for what?"
CIN_TP_HumansAreObsolete_10="Whatever alien DNA ADVENT wishes to insert. Sectoid. Muton. Even the species our soldiers refer to as "Berserker"."
CIN_TP_HumansAreObsolete_11="In all cases human genetic material serves as a bonding agent holding the strands together."
CIN_TP_HumansAreObsolete_12="Human Material. You mean the stuff we found at the Blacksite facility."
CIN_TP_HumansAreObsolete_13="Precisely. The key component in their soldier manufacturing process."
CIN_TP_HumansAreObsolete_14="So, we've been fighting ourselves this entire time."
CIN_TP_HumansAreObsolete_15="In a way. But I believe there's more to it than that."
CIN_TP_HumansAreObsolete_16="The Human DNA in this specimen bears one key difference from the entirety of the sequences decoded in the Shadow Chamber. Psionic sensitivity. Given the sheer volume of strands involved this cannot be accidental."
CIN_TP_HumansAreObsolete_17="The screening process at the clinics. Avatar."
CIN_TP_HumansAreObsolete_18="The potential power of a being created with this template is...significant. Central, had we not intercepted it before the process was completed..."
CIN_TP_HumansAreObsolete_19="I know Doctor. Continue your research. Let us know if you find anything else."

CIN_TP_AlienFortressRevealed_01="Hate to do this... But you're the only one who can pull this off. You know I'd go myself if I could."
CIN_TP_AlienFortressRevealed_02="The gateway is primed. Is the subject prepared?"
CIN_TP_AlienFortressRevealed_03="Ready."
CIN_TP_AlienFortressRevealed_04="I hardwired what was left of the Codex brain into Rover. It should be emitting the same signal the Codex used to pass through the gateway."
CIN_TP_AlienFortressRevealed_05="Excellent - let us begin."
CIN_TP_AlienFortressRevealed_06="We've already seen the Codex opening a similar rift in the field. I am sure your device will be fine."
CIN_TP_AlienFortressRevealed_07="There. We're set to record across all spectrums. Remember. Go in, take some quick readings, then come right back through. OK?"
CIN_TP_AlienFortressRevealed_08="Whoa... Are you seeing this?!"
CIN_TP_AlienFortressRevealed_09="It appears our signal has been received. Increasing power."
CIN_TP_AlienFortressRevealed_10="Doesn't look like anyplace we've been before... or any place on Earth for that matter."
CIN_TP_AlienFortressRevealed_11="Perhaps this is the source. The Aliens' "seat of power" if you will. Secured beyond any physical limitations."
CIN_TP_AlienFortressRevealed_12="Only one way to find out."
CIN_TP_AlienFortressRevealed_13="Go on. We're counting on you."
CIN_TP_AlienFortressRevealed_14="That is definitely not fine, Doctor."
CIN_TP_AlienFortressRevealed_15="The process did work. There was an instant where the device was in-between locations. However, once that occurred the gateway called for a second signature. An organic signature. When we could not provide one, it generated a sort of feedback pulse."
CIN_TP_AlienFortressRevealed_16="Obviously."
CIN_TP_AlienFortressRevealed_17="If the codex creates the door, this organic signature must surely be the key."
CIN_TP_AlienFortressRevealed_18="Well we better make sure we have the right key before we try again. I would hate for this to occur on something "organic.""
CIN_TP_AlienFortressRevealed_19="Agreed. I'll report our findings to the Commander immediately."

CIN_TP_AvatarAutopsy_01="This creature represents a near perfect fusion of human and Elder DNA.  Though remarkable, it appears as if the creature were unfinished, perhaps why we were able to ultimately defeat it.  Still this can lead me to only one logical conclusion..."
CIN_TP_AvatarAutopsy_02="We had such hope for you..."
CIN_TP_AvatarAutopsy_03="I believe we have found our Avatar."

CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_01="It won't be easy, but I think it's the only option we have at this point."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_02="Agreed. We must inform the Commander immediately."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_03="Go right ahead."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_04="Commander. Central."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_05="The shadow chamber has completed its analysis of the Avatar's DNA. It has identified the genetic sequence necessary to travel through the Psionic gate."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_05a="Perfect.  We can finally shut this Avatar project down for good."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_06="However the gate requires more than a mere transmission of genetic data."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_07="The sequence has to be part of a live subject."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_07a="The key only works in lock-step with the signal."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_08="We don't have time to find another one of those things. Let alone capture it."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_09="No. That part we can handle. We make our own."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_10="You're serious?"
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_11="Quite. Though the specimen before us is damaged beyond repair, it has provided us with its complete genetic blueprint."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_12="We already possess an unaltered Avatar template from the Forge facility. That, combined with the genetic material we recovered at the black site, should allow us to replicate the procedure here."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_13="So...what's the catch?"
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_14="Yes, that. Without an Elder consciousness driving it, the new Avatar would remain as lifeless as the one before us. While I can develop its body, I cannot create the mind to drive it.  "
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_15="But I can... in a way, by manipulating the new Avatar via the psionic network."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_16="You wanna operate one of these things...by remote control."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_17="Not exactly. And definitely not me."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_18="Interfacing directly with their network would cause severe, if not fatal trauma to an unprepared central nervous system. As it stands, we only know of one individual who has survived that kind of ordeal."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_19="That was different. The stasis suit..."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_20="Created the perfect interface to the network. One tailored to your specific biology, Commander. Of any human candidate, you are the most likely to survive the connection."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_21="Most likely is not good enough, Doctor."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_22="It is the only answer I can give you. And our only option to traverse the alien portal."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_23="We need to come up with a game plan before we charge through the enemy's front door."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt1_24="Which will give you some time to think about this, Commander."


CIN_TP_PreFinalMission_01="Priority message for the Commander coming through on a secure channel, sir."
CIN_TP_PreFinalMission_02="On Screen."
CIN_TP_PreFinalMission_03="Sir, it's coming from the ADVENT Network tower."
CIN_TP_PreFinalMission_04="You heard me. He's taking a big risk contacting us like this."
CIN_TP_PreFinalMission_05="Hello Commander. You and your crew are to be commended. Your efforts in rebuilding the resistance network and uncovering the truth about the Avatar project have been admirable. I only wish I had better news to report."
CIN_TP_PreFinalMission_06="When does he ever?"
CIN_TP_PreFinalMission_07="ADVENT is not taking the death of an Elder lightly and in turn have greatly accelerated the final stages of their Avatar Project. A plan is now in place for the rapid processing of all non-essential human life. To begin immediately."
CIN_TP_PreFinalMission_08="Very soon ADVENT's Speaker will announce a breakthrough in gene therapy. A final treatment for the human condition. Billions will flock to gene therapy clinics across the globe. They will never return."
CIN_TP_PreFinalMission_09="I have managed to secure tactical data and access codes to the ADVENT Network Tower. The Speaker's address will be broadcast live to a global audience via this facility - the whole of ADVENT's network will be listening."
CIN_TP_PreFinalMission_10="It is this hubris that we must use against them."
CIN_TP_PreFinalMission_11="The information I am sending you should allow Doctor Tygan and Chief Engineer Shen to take control of the transmission and disrupt their entire network from within."
CIN_TP_PreFinalMission_12="Though my hope is that this disruption will confuse the enemy's forces long enough to allow your final assault a chance of success, I ask one more thing of you."
CIN_TP_PreFinalMission_13="Take what you have learned. Let the world know what is happening here. Wake them up. Broadcast the truth. Before there is no one left to listen."
CIN_TP_PreFinalMission_14="It seems we are both out of time."
CIN_TP_PreFinalMission_15="Farewell Commander."

CIN_TP_BroadcastTruth_01="Firebrand has cleared the perimeter, Sir. Meeting limited resistance."
CIN_TP_BroadcastTruth_02="Well done, Doctor..."
CIN_TP_BroadcastTruth_03="Yes, it would appear the feedback pulse is having the intended effect."
CIN_TP_BroadcastTruth_04="Shen? Status... Did it work?"
CIN_TP_BroadcastTruth_05="ADVENT assures us this breakthrough will be available to all citizens immediately."
CIN_TP_BroadcastTruth_06="We go live to the Speaker for more..."
CIN_TP_BroadcastTruth_07="Fellow citizens. For 20 years we have put our trust in ADVENT, in the Elders - because we believed a better future is possible for all. Today, that trust, that belief, has been rewarded."
CIN_TP_BroadcastTruth_08="ADVENT peacekeeping forces are traveling across the world carrying the greatest gift from the elders."
CIN_TP_BroadcastTruth_09="A revolutionary gene therapy yes. But so much more. This is an end to disease. To decay. To pain. The beginnings of a new tomorrow. Available to all of us. Today."
CIN_TP_BroadcastTruth_10="Truly humanity finally takes its rightful place amongst the stars."

CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt2_01="There. I've infused this material with the entirety of our viable Elder DNA. We won't get another chance at this."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt2_02="Final connection is set. Power levels adequate. One more look at the buffer..."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt2_03="Shen. Watched you go over this thing 50 times. Take a breath."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt2_04="We're ready."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt2_05="Synthesis nearing completion."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt2_06="Now Lily!"
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt2_07="Initiating network connection."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt2_08="Give em hell..."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt2_09="Gate is primed and ready, sir."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt2_10="Patch me through. Alright people. The world got its wake up call."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt2_11="And now they know the truth."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt2_12="ADVENT is a lie. And their time is up. They've got a full fledged war on their hands now!"
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt2_13="While the aliens struggle to contain our world, we're gonna make a move on theirs."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt2_14="It won't be easy."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt2_15="But you're used to that."
CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt2_16="You did what was needed. You never gave up the fight."

CIN_TP_DarkVolunteer_pt2b_01="You are XCOM. And you're gonna end this! Humanity is counting on us, people. Good luck, Commander."

CIN_Victory_01="Shen, tell me you've got a Plan B here."
CIN_Victory_02="Nice work."
CIN_Victory_03="Wasn't anything on my end. This shouldn't even be possible. Unless..."
CIN_Victory_04="Commander, whatever it is you're doing, it's working.  Just make sure you save enough juice for your own trip home."
CIN_Victory_05="Commander! You okay?! We just lost contact with..."
CIN_Victory_06="Betrayer!"
CIN_Victory_07="What the hell is happening here, Doctor?!"
CIN_Victory_08="It's the Elders! They're overwhelming our link...enveloping the Commander's consciousness!"
CIN_Victory_09="Then sever the connection!"
CIN_Victory_10="We do that, we risk a complete overload!"
CIN_Victory_11="We will reclaim what was given. We will be whole once more."
CIN_Victory_12="No!"
CIN_Victory_13="Your victory here means the end for all others."
CIN_Victory_14="It will follow you, as it followed us."
CIN_Victory_15="You are not ready."
CIN_Victory_16="We must not fail."
CIN_Victory_17="Vitals stabilizing. Synaptic activity returning to acceptable levels."
CIN_Victory_18="And one trans-dimensional Psionic network down for the count."
CIN_Victory_19="Mission accomplished, Commander."
CIN_Victory_20="This is the Liberation Network broadcasting on all frequencies. ADVENT is in full retreat across all areas..."
CIN_Victory_21="Heavy fighting continues in the city centers as ADVENT forces attempt to regroup..."
CIN_Victory_22="We're barely keeping up with the flood of refugees here as people continue to desert the ADVENT-controlled city centers."
CIN_Victory_23="Full curfew remains in effect as the administration deals with the ongoing crisis."
CIN_Victory_24="To all of you in the occupied zones - hold your ground, continue the fight. We promise you, help is the on the way."

CIN_GameOver_01="Loyal citizens - I stand before you truly humbled. So many lives lost, so many needless sacrifices endured, as we have struggled to cope with those who would see our great coalition fall. Today, our struggle ends."
CIN_GameOver_02="XCOM is no more."
CIN_GameOver_03="ADVENT Peacekeepers have reduced the last of their strongholds to ashes. And with it, the fragmented remains of the old world are finally washed away."
CIN_GameOver_04="Thank you for your continued support. And thank you to the Elders for their guidance through this crisis."
CIN_GameOver_05="Long live Advent. Long Live the Elders."

CIN_Autopsy_Advent_01="Knowing that my past surgical experience is limited, I'm sure the crew appreciates that I hone my skills on fallen ADVENT forces before triaging our own wounded. To the uninitiated, the common ADVENT Trooper is seemingly human, the aliens having disguised its most glaring divergence from the human form with a carefully designed helmet."
CIN_Autopsy_AdventCaptain_01="The ADVENT Officers appear to be similar, if not physically the same, as the common ADVENT Trooper in terms of power and agility. However, field reports indicate a more developed mental acuity, as the Officers do provide tactical directives to the subordinate ADVENT forces."
CIN_Autopsy_AdventMec_01="These robotic units developed by ADVENT seem to be wholly autonomous, capable of targeting and engaging selected units without reliance on external verification. Although it falls on me to work through the initial disassembly, I fully intend on involving Shen in this process, as her knowledge of robotics far outweighs my own."
CIN_Autopsy_AdventShieldBearer_01="Physically the ADVENT Shieldbearers are quite similar to the bulk of ADVENT's forces, in that they are the product of careful genetic engineering that generally mirrors the human form. Most of their unique qualities come from a difference in equipment and armor, components I'm sure Shen would have an interest in examining."
CIN_Autopsy_AdventStunLancer_01="The ADVENT Stun Lancer was apparently outfitted with the intention of serving as a civilian peacekeeping unit within the city centers. Although they are equipped with weapons capable of administering non-lethal blows, recent reports indicate an increasingly aggressive stance taken by these units."
CIN_Autopsy_AdventTurret_01="The turrets we see employed by ADVENT throughout their various facilities and security checkpoints are automated much in the same way the alien mechanized units are. A significant amount of time was likely spent developing the optical sensors and targeting system, which I expect Shen will want to thoroughly examine following the disassembly process."
CIN_Autopsy_Andromedon_01="As initially speculated by Shen, it does in fact appear that this creature is restricted to the confines of its own hulking environmental suit. Unfortunately for our troops, the suit itself is a powerful physical threat regardless of the operator's status, as we learned with some astonishment in the field."
CIN_Autopsy_Archon_01="The product of an extensive fusion of both alien biological material and advanced mechanical support systems, the Archon is an unusually ornate design by alien standards. With an air of authority spurred by its distinctive appearance, I can only assume the aliens intended it to be something of a herald to the other forces."
CIN_Autopsy_Berserker_01="This fearsome creature, long referred to as a Berserker, is clearly of genetic relation to the other Muton species we've encountered in the field. For reasons yet unknown, this particular variant is unique in that it is altogether consumed by what can only be described as blind rage, a thirst for combat unlike any other creature we've encountered."
CIN_Autopsy_Chryssalid_01="Presumably the name Chryssalid derives from assumptions made previously about the creature's unusual means of reproduction. Although rumors have long prevailed about the existence of Zombies created as a byproduct of the Chryssalid gestation, recent reports seem to indicate a new, equally disturbing means of propagating their species."
CIN_Autopsy_Faceless_01="I'm at a loss for words to describe the difficulties we've had in attempting to handle this creature, affectionately known as the Faceless to our troops. The nebulous form of its physical structure, including a pliable, semi-solid outer layer, seems to be slowly degrading now that the creature has expired. There is also a pungent odor that only seems to grow stronger as time passes."
CIN_Autopsy_Gatekeeper_01="This specimen, henceforth referred to as the Gatekeeper, seems to harbor considerable Psionic power. As with the aliens other unique biomechanical field units, it will take some time to decipher the systems involved in its function."
CIN_Autopsy_Muton_01="Central Officer Bradford has personally substantiated claims that the massive front-line unit they call the Muton was actually at one time even larger than the specimen I have before me today. As it is, the creature is abnormally warm to the touch for a corpse, and I must say, it's disconcerting."
CIN_Autopsy_Sectoid_01="Though I was never witness to one myself, countless observers attest to the existence of a much smaller, less intimidating variant of the Sectoid that took part in the original invasion. In the time since, this new being, the product of clear genetic manipulation, is now a familiar face to our forces operating in the field."
CIN_Autopsy_Sectopod_01="From what I've been told, our troops took to calling this large robotic unit a Sectopod under the initial assumption that it was being controlled by a Sectoid pilot. On closer inspection, we can see that is not the case. Not unlike the mechanized ADVENT units, which were likely derived from the Sectopod itself, this machine seems to be entirely autonomous."
CIN_Autopsy_Viper_01="Although I would expect to be more growing accustomed to seeing the clear intermingling of both human and alien genetic material, I must admit, this reptilian creature with such distinctive human features is surprisingly unsettling. Invasion-era reports include references to a species with some reptilian qualities, but nothing as readily apparent as this."

CIN_WeaponIntro_Beam_01="The aliens aren't going to be happy when they see we've got energy weapons just like theirs now."
CIN_WeaponIntro_Magnetic_01="These magnetic-based weapons are a lot like the early Railgun prototypes. They fire projectiles at extremely high velocity."
